Guide to the International Studies Center Records, 1952-1957
Duke University. University Archives
International Studies Center records 1952-1957
Duke University. University Archives
Institute for International Education. International Studies Center.
0.5 linear feet Extent: 500 Items
The Institute Studies Center (ISC) sponsored programs in international education. From 1952-1957, Duke was a host institution for the IIE's INternational Studies Center. This was a summer orientation program for foreign students sponsored by the US State Department. For several weeks during the summer, contracted schools hosted students coming to study in the US and introduced them to American life. The ISC should not be confused with the Duke University Center for International Studies. Materials in the collection include administrative records, correspondence, reports, and black and white photographs of international students.
RL.01645
Language: Material in english
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Provenance
The International Studies Center Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1973 and 1978.
Historical Note
The Institute Studies Center (ISC) sponsored programs in international education. From 1952-1957, Duke was a host institution for the IIE's INternational Studies Center. This was a summer orientation program for foreign students sponsored by the US State Department. For several weeks during the summer, contracted schools hosted students coming to study in the US and introduced them to American life. The ISC should not be confused with the Duke University Center for International Studies.
Collection Overview
Materials in the collection include administrative records, correspondence, reports, and black and white photographs of international students.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Institute of International Education. International Studies Center; International Education -- North Carolina -- Durham; International Students; Students, Foreign
Related Material
Inventory of the Joseph C. Wetherby papers, 1930-1976.
University Archives, Duke University.
Preliminary Inventory of the Robin Chandler Duke Papers, [ca. 1930]-2003.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Arrivals & Departures, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957
  - Correspondence - Institute of International Education, 1957
  - Final Report, Scrapbook, etc., undated
  - Financial, 1955-1957
  - General Administrative, 1957
  - General Correspondence, 1957
  - General File, 1955
  - General File, 1956
  - Hints for Future Direction, 1956-1957
  - Hospitality, 1957
  - Reports, 1952-1957
  - Staff Reports, 1957
  - Student Reports, undated
  - T.V.A. Tour, 1956-1957